（ナルト）これって…
いったい　何の術だ！？
What jutsu is this anyway?!
《引き寄せる術に…
突きとばす術。
A jutsu that pulls…
A jutsu that repels…
A Summoning Jutsu…
口寄せの術に…
忍術を吸い取る術》
A jutsu that absorbs ninjutsu!
ペインの術
全部使えるみてえだけどもよぉ！
You have all of Pain's jutsu!
この術は知らねえぞ！
But I'm…not familiar with this one!
だ～っ！　そうだ！
Oh, right!
忍術を吸い取るって
さっき確認したばっかじゃん。
I just confirmed that he can absorb
ninjutsu a minute ago!
俺のアホ！
Stupid me!
Nagato! What the hell is
that jutsu anyway?!
長門　何だってばよ　この術
教えてくれってばよ！？
Tell me!
《ダメだ　完全に操られてる》
No good!
He's completely being controlled…
《長門：地獄道》
Jigokudo!
《こいつは確か…
生き返らせるペインの術！》
Hey, wait… This is…
It's the reviver Pain's jutsu!
何　狙ってんだ　いったい！？
What are you after?!
《人間道で　魂を引き抜き→
Use Ningendo to extract
their soul and kill them off.
いったん殺して
地獄道で　魂と肉体を隠し→
Hide their bodies and souls
with Jigokudo…
持ち帰って
僕のもとで生き返らせる。
and bring them back to me,
so that I can revive them.
マダラに見つかることなく→
I can make the Jinchuriki mine
without Madara finding out.
人柱力たちを
僕のものにできる方法っと…。
さて　他に
どんなのがあったっけなぁ…》
Now then, what else could he do?
Damn it! So you're not gonna
give me any answers, after all?!
クソーッ！　やっぱ
なんにも答えてくんねえのかよ！
あの生き返らせる術を
どうやって使うってんだ！？
How does that reviving jutsu work again?
しかも　これ
魂みたいの出ちゃってっけど！
This stuff…
It's like my soul's coming out!
力抜けるし　嫌な予感しかしねえ！
And I'm losing strength…
I'm getting a bad feeling about this!
The Acknowledged One
うわ～！
《修羅道！》
Shurado!
《キラービー：カラクリの鎧を
召喚したのか！？》
What did he summon? A fancy armor?
おっちゃん！
Octopops!
まさに
いろんな手を使う　術が飛び交う。
He sure uses a lot of hands.
To change tactics and his stance.
ナルト　九尾との綱引きを思い出せ！
Naruto, remember when you had
that tug-of-war with the Nine Tails!
うっ…　うわ～！
（イタチ）スサノオ！
Susano'o!
イタチ…。
これがスサノオ　すげえのぉ。
Itachi!
So this is the Susano'o!
Man, what a show!
助かったってばよ。　サンキュー　イタチ。
You're a lifesaver! Thanks, Itachi!
なんだ　この忍者は。
はっきり言って→
What kind of ninja is he?!
Damn, he's strong! Fool, ya fool!
むちゃ強えじゃねえかよ。
バカ野郎　この野郎。
ペイン六道っつって→
He's known as Pain,
六道仙人の力を持ってんだから
そりゃ強えよ！
and has the strength of
the Sage of Six Paths.
So, of course he's strong!
それに今回は
死体　操ってるんじゃなく→
And this time, we're facing him,
not his corpse puppets!
本人だから
力も動きも桁違いだ！
So his power and moves are
in a different league.
（カブト）そうだ　まだ星にして
捕まえるってのもあるな。
Oh yeah…
We can still use that planet jutsu
to capture them…
《地爆天星》
Planetary Devastation.
くるぞ！
Here it comes!
うわっ！
何だ　ありゃ　よう！
What is that?!
あの黒い玉
相当の引力があるようだ。
That black sphere looks like
it has enormous gravitational pull!
この術…　前にも　やられた。
He got me with this jutsu once!
マジやべえ　マジやべえ！
It's super bad, it's super bad!
これもくらったら　終わりだ！
If you get caught in it, it's over!
おい　ナルト。
なに！？
Hey, Naruto…
What?!
くらって終わりなら
お前は　なんで生きてる？
If it's a sure death,
how come you're still alive?
えっ…。
アハハハ　なら大丈夫　この勝負。
Well then, no need to worry,
about our victory.
って笑ってる場合じゃ
ねえんだよ！
This is no time to be laughing!
なんで　この状況で
余裕ぶっかませんだよ！
How can you be so easygoing
when we're in a bind like this?!
いいか？　捕まったら
二度と抜け出せねえ！
If we're caught,
we'll never be able to get out!
すげえ力で
引きつけられんだぞ！
Its gravitational power is awesome!
前ん時は　九尾の暴走で　たまたま
どうにかなったんだけど…。
I got out only because
of Nine Tails' rampage…
余裕でいるんじゃない。
分析には冷静さがいる。
It's not about being easygoing.
Analysis requires calm.
さっき長門が投げた
黒いかたまりが→
It's safe to assume that the mass
that Nagato threw earlier
中心の核になってるとみていい。
is the central core of gravity.
おそらく　あれを破壊すればいい。
We need to destroy it.
３人おのおのの
最強遠距離忍術で→
We'll attack the center simultaneously,
each of us using our most powerful
long-distance ninjutsu!
一斉に中央を攻撃する。
こんな状況じゃ
うまく中央を狙えねえ！
We can't aim properly under
these conditions!
狙わなくても当たる。
Our jutsu will make contact,
even if we don't aim correctly.
中央からの
この強すぎる吸引力を→
This tactic takes advantage of
the core's powerful gravitational pull.
逆に利用する算段だ。
どんな術にも
弱点となる穴は　必ずある。
Every jutsu has a weakness!
オーケー！
はやっ！
Okay.
That was fast!
よっしゃ～　俺も！
All right… Me too!
八坂ノ勾玉！
尾獣玉！
Yasaka Beads!
Tailed Beast Bomb!
風遁　螺旋手裏剣！
Wind Style, Rasen Shuriken!
すまないな…　イタチ。
Forgive me…Itachi.
元へ戻ったか。　十拳剣だ。
You're back.
This is the Totsuka Blade…
((大蛇丸：フフフ…　うっ　うぅ…。
フフフ…　この程度の攻撃で
私がやられると思って…　あっ。
Do you think an attack
like this is going to stop me?
この剣は　まさか　十拳剣！？
This sword…
This is the Totsuka Blade!
イタチ　あなたが隠し持って…　あぁ！
Itachi, you had this hidden
with you all along!
（白ゼツ）何なの！？　あの剣。
What is that sword?
（黒ゼツ）十拳剣…　別名
酒刈の太刀と呼ばれる封印剣だ。
It's the Totsuka Blade.
Also known as the Sakegari Blade.
突き刺した者を　酔夢の幻術世界に
永久に飛ばし→
It seals away all it pierces,
into a world of eternal genjutsu.
封じ込めるといわれる。
(剣そのものが　封印術を帯びた
草薙剣のひと振りだ))
The blade itself is imbued
with a sealing jutsu
and is a variant of the Kusanagi Blade.
封印術を帯びた剣だ。
すぐに封印する。
It's a sword that possesses
a sealing jutsu.
You will be sealed away soon.
何か　言い残すことはあるか？
Do you have any last words?
ナルト…　俺は
師匠のところへ戻って→
Naruto, I will return to our master's side
and watch your story unfold.
お前の物語を見ておくとするよ。
俺から言わせりゃ　お前は
三部作目の完結編だ。
If you ask me, you are
the final volume of the trilogy.
一部が　自来也…　完璧だった。
Jiraiya was the perfect first volume.
だが　二部作目ってのは
たいがい駄作になる。
But the second volume
was a failure…me.
俺のようにな。
師にも認めてもらってない…。
One that our master
would not acknowledge.
シリーズの出来ってのは　三作目
完結編で決まる。
The series will culminate with
the third and final volume.
駄作を帳消しにするくらいの
最高傑作になってくれよ…　ナルト。
You must make it
a masterpiece…
One that will completely overshadow
the failure of the middle volume, Naruto!
じゃあな。
Farewell.
《長門め。
やはり機動力に欠けていたか。
Damn Nagato…
He wasn't mobile enough!
口寄せ輪廻眼による共通視界で
機動力を補うつもりが…》
I hoped to compensate his lack of mobility
with the summoned Rinnegan,
which would give him
the same field of vision.
But Itachi was able to target it with
his kunai even from his blind spots.
（カブト）死角からクナイを当てる
イタチの手裏剣術。
That's his shuriken jutsu.
さすがに　かわせなかったか。
Even Nagato couldn't dodge it.
I have no choice,
but to bring out my special reserve!
そろそろ
とっておきを出すしかないね。
This Reanimation Jutsu or
whatever they call it stinks!
このエドテンとかいう術
気に食わねえ。
戦いたくねえ人と戦わされる。
Guys are forced to fight,
even when they don't want to.
おそらく他の戦地でも
そうなんだろ？
This is happening at
other battlegrounds too, right?
穢土転生は俺が止める。
I will put a stop to
the Reanimation Jutsu.
I leave Madara to you two.
マダラはお前たちに任せる。
ここに来る途中に
穢土転生のやつと戦った。
We fought with a Reanimated Ninja
on the way here.
砂の忍が　そいつを封印はしたが→
The Sand shinobi sealed him…
どうやら
殺せはしないようだ　オーケー？
But it seems he can't be killed, okay?
この術は弱点のない
完璧な術だそうだ　オーケー？
This is a perfect jutsu that
has no weaknesses, okay?
さっき言ったはずだ。
I told you earlier.
どんな術にも弱点となる穴が
必ずあると。
There is a weakness in every jutsu.
どうだろうな。
I wonder about that…
いや　俺が止める。
さっきも言ったはずだ。
No, I'll stop him!
Like I said…
Leave the rest to me!
あとは俺に任せてくれ。
影分身の術。
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
九尾チャクラモードの使いすぎだ。
それ以上　分身するな　ナルト。
You've used Nine Tails
Chakra Mode too much.
No more clones right now, Naruto!
一人で無理しようとするな。
Don't try to do everything yourself.
この穢土転生を止めるためには
俺がうってつけだ。
I am the best one to put
an end to the Reanimation Jutsu.
考えがある。
I also have an idea.
この戦争は　全部俺が引き受ける。
I'll put an end to this war…
それが俺の役目なんだ！
It's my responsibility!
ハァ　ハァ。
I'll admit that you're stronger
than before.
お前は　確かに前とは違い
強くなった。
だが　そのせいで大事なことを
見失いかけてもいるようだな。
But because of that,
you seem to have lost sight
of what's truly important.
いいか　よく覚えておけ。
Now listen carefully.
お前を嫌っていた里の皆が
お前を慕いはじめ→
The people of the village,
who once abhorred you,
have begun to admire you.
仲間だと思ってくれるように
なったのは→
They think of you as a comrade.
お前が他人の存在を意識し
認められたいと→
It's because you fought hard
for their acceptance.
いちずに頑張ったからだ。
お前は　皆のおかげで
ここまで来られたと言ったな。
You once said it was
everyone who cares about you
who helped you get
where you are now.
力をつけた今
他人の存在を忘れ　おごり→
If you forget others because
you now have power,
and become arrogant and egotistical,
個に執着すれば　いずれ
マダラのようになっていくぞ。
you'll eventually become
just like Madara.
どんなに強くなろうとも
すべてを背負おうとするな。
No matter how powerful
you become,
do not try to shoulder
everything alone.
そうすれば必ず失敗する。
If you do, you will surely fail.
お前の父　ミナトが
火影としてあったのは→
Your father, Minato, was able to
fulfill his duty as the Hokage
母　クシナや仲間の存在が
あったからこそだ。
because he had your mother, Kushina,
and his comrades at his side.
You share your father's dream,
don't you?
お前の夢は確か父と同じだったな。
なら　覚えておけ。
Then don't ever forget…
火影になった者が
皆に認められるんじゃない。
Becoming the Hokage doesn't mean
people will acknowledge you.
皆から認められた者が
火影になるんだ。
But when the people
acknowledge you,
you can become the Hokage.
仲間を忘れるな。
Never forget your friends!
ナルト…
俺は　イルカってのと約束してんだ。
Naruto…
I swore to that Iruka fella.
Simply put, that I'd protect ya.
だいたい　お前を守るってな。
一人じゃ行かせねえぞ。
I won't let you go alone, bro!
Cuz' I'm still alive, and rarin' to go.
そもそも　俺は　まだ生きてる。
ピンピン！
((イルカ：だだをこねるな！
俺にとって　お前はな…。
Don't act like a spoiled brat!
To me, you are…
俺にとって　お前は
大切な生徒の一人だ。
To me, you are…
An important student.
そして　弟のようにも思ってる。
And…I think of you as
my little brother.
敵のボスは　お前を
全勢力をあげて狙ってくる。
The en
みすみす　そんな危ない所へ→
お前を行かせたいと
思うわけないだろ。
(それに　お前ばかりが
全部背負い込むことはないんだ))
たしかに　俺が
なんとかしなきゃダメなんだって→
思い込みすぎてたかもしんねえ。
カーッ！
な　なんで！？
シスイの眼は十数年は役に立たない。
もう　サスケのときには
使えないだろうし→
それに　お前は
シスイの眼以上のものを持ってる。
え…。
それは　シスイと同じ心だ。
シスイが渡したかった本当のものは
それだ。
もう眼はいらない。
今のお前なら→
こんな眼を使わなくても
サスケを止められる。
今なら　あんたも直接サスケに会える。
今度こそ…。
いや。
俺は一人で何でもしようとし
失敗した。
今度は　それこそ仲間に任せるさ。
((サスケは　お前に任せる))
ただ強いってだけの忍じゃないな
あんたってやつは。
キラービー　ナルトを頼む。
オウ　ヨウ！
イタチ！
俺たちも行こう　ビーのおっちゃん！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』→
２時間スペシャル！